In the last lecture you'll learn that in react 16, you can actually return adjacent elements in some
Son dersin 16 nolu ilemde reneceksiniz ki, baz
circumstances. For one of the circumstances props children,
durumlarda, pervanelerin ocuklarndan birinin komu eleri geri getirebilirsiniz.
we created this auxiliary component
Bu yardmc bileeni yarattk.
and I told you that it's a higher order component called like this because all it does is it basically
Sana syledim, bunun nedeni daha yksek bir dzen bileenidir, nk yapt ey temelde tamamlar
wraps another component, doesn't really do much else but does something with that wrapping component,
ve bir bileen gerekten ok fazla ey yapmaz, ancak o rap bileeniyle bir eyler yapar.
in this case simply output it with props children so that we can use this advantage or take advantage
Bu durumda, bu avantaj kullanabilmemiz iin veya 60'n yeniden dzenlenmesinin bu yeni zelliinden
of this new feature of react 16.
faydalanabilmemiz iin, yalnzca pervane ocuklaryla ktlar.
Now you can also create higher order components and by the way you will often use some when using third
bileenlerini de oluturabilir ve bu arada parti paketleri iin bazlar daha sk kullanrsnz.
party packages
Artk yksek sipari
that add a certain logic to a component. Some logic you might need in multiple components which you don't
Bir bileene belirli bir mantkta lecek, bunlara her birine yazmak istemediiniz birden fazla bileende ihtiyacnz
want to write into each of them,
olan baz mantklar.
for example share a logged in user, you will see some higher order components throughout this course,
rnein, bir kilitli kullancy paylatnzda, bu ders iin yksek sipari bileenleri grrsnz.
let's add one for our demo project here though. For the person.js component,
Demo projemiz iin bir tane daha ekleyelim, J. kiisi iin. S. bileen.
we wrap it in a div with classes, person as a class name, in app.js we do the same, a div with classes
Biz bir snf ad olarak snf kiilerle bir div iine sarn ve aslnda evet snflar app ile ayn
app
gn yapmak.
but it would be cool if we could use a higher order component which does that,
Bunu yapan daha yksek dereceli bir bileen kullanabilirsek iyi olur.
now there are actually two approaches we could take, I'll show both. The first one is the maybe with class.js
Aslnda iki yaklam var, her ikisi de birincisi, belki snf
file which is a constant withClass equal to
J ile sonbahar olarak snfa eit snftan bir sabit olan.
function of course where all we do is we return some jsx where we have this wrapping div and there,
levimiz elbette ki yaptmz tek ey, Dith'i sarmalamak zorunda olduumuz baz j x deerlerini geri
we might set a class name, receive props classes, this is the expectation of this component and then output
getirmek ve orada snfn adn alabiliriz, alnan pervane Colossus, bu bileenin beklentisidir
props children in between.
ve daha sonra kt ocuklar arar.
Next we of course need to import react from react because this will be transformed to react create
Sonra elbette reaksiyondan yeniden aktarmaya ihtiyacmz var, nk bu elemana tepki
element and then export default withClass.
olarak dntrlecek ve ardndan snf varsaylan olarak verecektir.
Now we can use the with Class wrapper here,
imdi bunu Classen Rapparee ile birlikte kullanabiliriz.
for example in the app.js file, let's quickly import it, let's import with class from up one level hoc with
rnein, ABD'nin dnde hzl bir ekilde ithal edelim, snfa bir seviye Agios C'den ithal
class
edelim.
and now, let's wrap it.
Ve imdi onu saralm.
So let's wrap our component with the withClass component, here
yleyse, bileenimizi class bileeniyle sarmalm.
we now have withClass and close with class.
Artk CLOS ile beraber snfla kapandk.
So we replace the div with it
Dave'i deitirdik.
and as we configured withClass, we expect to get classes as a property.
Snf ile yaplandrldnda snflar bir mlk olarak almamz bekliyoruz.
So we should pass this, props children of course is the part we passed between the opening and closing
ancak snf mlkne ihtiyacmz var ve tabii ki Colossus uygulamas olmal.
tags, so this part, but we need the class property and this should of course be classes app.
Bu yzden tabii ki bu pervane ocuklarn gemeliyiz, al ve kapan etiketleri arasnda getiimiz blm bu blm bu yzden bu,
So we basically replaced the div which has class name with withClass which is classes so we saved
Temel olarak, snflar olan Dave ile snflar olan snflar deitirdik, bylece
a few characters which we then spanned instead of the div.
lm yerine harcadmz birka karakter kaydedildi.
Still it's a nice example for one possible higher order of component,
Yine de muhtemel bir yksek bileen dzeni iin gzel bir rnek.
it doesn't do anything than wrap the content in a div and assign this css class.
Hibir ey yapmaz, daha sonra ierii bir div iine sarar ve bir C S S snf atar.
If we now save this, get the same styling and behavior as before with withClasses and of course we can also
imdilik, kaydetme, snflarla daha nce olduu gibi ayn ekilde bir stile sahip oluyor ve tabii ki bunu
add this to person where we have the same behavior,
da ayn davranlara sahip olduumuz kii olduumuz kiilere de ekleyebiliyoruz.
a wrapping div.
Bir sarg fark.
Let's quickly do this, let's import withClass here too,
Hadi abucak balayalm, burada da snfla ieri aktaralm.
let's go up a couple of levels until we reach the top level,
En st seviyeye gelene kadar birka seviye yukar kalm.
go to hoc, import with class and then again as before in the app.js file,
Agios'a gidip, CLOS ile ie aktarldn ve daha sonra sonbaharda olduu gibi tekrar gelmesini isteyin.
replace this div here with withClass and class name
Bu lmn, madde ve snf adyla deitir.
now with classes because it is the property withClass expects.
nk snflarla imdi CLOS ile mlkiyet beklemektedir.
And now with that, if we relaod this, get the same styling as before with our custom higher order component.
Ve imdi bununla engellersek, daha nce olduu gibi ayn yksek standartl bileeni elde edersiniz.